in cycle 5 we will try to issue this
next instruction which is a divide this
divide is going to look for this type of
a unit and find it so we're gonna mark
that ml 2 is not full we're gonna say
that this has issued in cycle 5 we're
gonna look at F 0 and F 6 as our inputs
F 0 comes from element 1 F 6 is actually
in the register file because this
doesn't save so for example if this load
has been a little bit later we would
have to wait for it but because it's
done we can read 7 point 1 and put it
here and then we're gonna rename f10 to
point to this ml 2 which is where we put
the divide and that concludes the issue
for this cycle now as far as the
dispatch is concerned we have already
dispatched this load and there is
nothing else that is ready to dispatch
so we don't dispatch anything this cycle
in this cycle this load is still
executing it's gonna broadcast this
result in the very next cycle in cycle 6
and there is no result that gets
broadcast in this cycle either so we are
basically done with cycle 5 now let's
look at cycle 6 in cycle 6 we're going
to try to dispatch this add there is a
unit available so we will succeed in
dispatching it f8 and f2 are gonna be a
d1 and ld2 renamed f6 to point to the 82
now which is where we put this
instruction and that concludes the
issuing of this instruction now let's
look at whether we can dispatch
something well in cycle 5 this
instruction is still executing so in
cycle 6 is gonna write the result but
until that writes the result nothing is
ready really to execute so basically we
don't really dispatch anything but there
will be a write result by the load as a
result of this several things will
happen first of all we will deposit the
result of the load which is whatever is
at address 2 45 to the register f2 so
let's say that our f2 just became I
don't know minus 2.5 we can then provide
this value also to all of the things
that are waiting for ld2 in this case
there are several instructions so the
operand here matches
the two so minus 2.5 will be captured
here
and we are no longer waiting for it the
second operand of this instruction also
matches we are going to capture it here
and mark this is no longer waiting for
it and then the first operand of this
matches it minus 2.5 so we're gonna
unmarked it here too and finally because
this entry match is LD 2 we're gonna
change the rat to one small point to the
register file so this concludes the
writing of the result remember that
because now these instructions are
actually ready to go but because that
happens kind of towards the end of the
cycle we consider that they cannot
really dispatch in the same cycle
because we are considering that we
cannot first broadcast the result and
then dispatch instructions that use that
result it's easier if we then first try
to dispatch instructions and then
broadcast the result because if we now
consider what can dispatch this looks
like it can dispatch so we need to
remember that the broadcast has happened
in the same cycle and this really is not
eligible for dispatch yet so that's why
we did kind of dispatch before broadcast
similarly it could help if we just did
the you know dispatch and then issue and
then broadcast just so that you know
kind of we don't consider things that
have just issued for dispatch but that
is it because only one thing gets to
dispatch and it's very very quick so in
cycle 6 we have issued an instruction we
have broadcast the result and nothing
really has been dispatched so now it's
time to consider what happens in cycle 7